<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio on James Patten</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolio on James Patten</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Importer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/data-importer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/data-importer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-the-problem-with-current-data-tooling&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the problem with current data tooling?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently &amp;lsquo;ETL&amp;rsquo; (extract, transform, load) is a job that is done by Data Engineers between a source and a target system. Usually the target system is is a data warehouse such as Snowflake, BigQuery, or Redshift.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But non technical users also perform &amp;lsquo;ETL&amp;rsquo; tasks all the time. Marketing teams import data into their product management tool to build reports. Sales teams import data into their CRM to enrich their pipeline. Operations teams import order data into work management tools to manage their supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canopact (acquired)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/canopact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/canopact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prior to the rise of collaboration tools like Slack and Microsoft Teams, internal communications tooling was mostly focused around email and intranet sites.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the onset of remote and hybrid working, accellerated by global lockdowns, more and more companies adopted collaboration tools as their primary internal communications channel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Canopact is an internal communications app for Slack, which provides some of the email/intranet functionality that isn&amp;rsquo;t available natively on the platform (e.g. newlsetters, engagement analytics, alias posting etc.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
