<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on James Patten</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on James Patten</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to start and grow a platform product</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/platform-product/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/platform-product/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A platform product/business, also referred to as a &amp;lsquo;plugin&amp;rsquo; or &amp;rsquo;embedded software,&amp;rsquo; is a product that lives inside a larger platform. Slack apps, Shopify apps, Monday apps etc. are all examples of such products.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-build-inside-another-platform&#34;&gt;Why build inside another platform?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve built two profitable platform products so far (Canopact, Data Importer). I&amp;rsquo;ve also tried to build stand-alone SaaS products, which were an order of magnitude harder to launch and get off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The best way to get early users in a market you have no experience in</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/early-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/early-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conventional start-up wisdom tells us that the best way to get early traction for your product is to launch into a market/industry you already have an understanding of, a network within, an unfair advantage on etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is very good advice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But sometimes (against our better judgement) we don&amp;rsquo;t want to build a product inside a market we already know well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re excited about a problem in a different market, bored to death of the industry you&amp;rsquo;ve been working in for 10+ years, or think there&amp;rsquo;s more growth potential in another area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I prioritise feature requests for Data Importer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/feature-prioritization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/feature-prioritization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I get a fair amount of feature requests for Data Importer (currently 10+ per week). Here&amp;rsquo;s how I go about deciding what to work on and when.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a period of just prioritising based on vibes (which I still do sometimes), I thought it was time to look at some of the popular feature request frameworks out there and see which ones would best align with the product I&amp;rsquo;m building.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
